<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Observations from the moderate resolution imaging spectroradiometer (MODIS) were used in combination with a large data set of Field measurements to map woody above-ground biomass (AGB) across tropical Africa. We generated a best-quality cloud-free mosaic of MODIS satellite reflectance observations for the period 2000-2003 and used a regression tree model to predict AGB at 1 km resolution. Results based on a cross-validation approach show that the model explained 82% of the variance in AGB, with a root mean square error of 50.5 Mg ha-1 for a range of biomass between 0 and 454 Mg ha-1 . Analysis of lidar metrics from the Geoscience Laser Altimetry System (GLAS), which are sensitive to vegetation structure, indicate that the model successfully captured the regional distribution of AGB. The results showed a strong positive correlation ( R2 = 0.90) between the GLAS height metrics and predicted AGB.</abstract>
      <purpose>The United Nations Framework Convention in Climate Change (UNFCCC) recognized the important role of deforestation in the carbon cycle, particularly in tropical forestes ecosystems. This map is a step towards developing baseline estimates of Above-ground biomass for carbon-credit allocation schemes to reduce emissions from deforestation and forest degradation (REDD) in in tropical Africa. This represents satellite-derived baseline estimates of above-ground biomass for the Democratic Republic of the Congo.</purpose>
      <supplinf />
    </descript>
    <useconst>When referencing these data please use: Baccini, A., Laporte, N., Goetz, S.J., Sun, M. and Dong, H. 2008. A first map of tropical Africa&amp;apos;s above-ground biomass derived from satellite imagery. Environmental Research Letters 3. stacks.iop.org/ERL/3/045011 Environmental Research Letters 3. stacks.iop.org/ERL/3/045011</useconst>
    <datacred>Baccini, A., Laporte, N., Goetz, S.J., Sun, M. and Dong, H. 2008. A first map of tropical Africa&amp;apos;s above-ground biomass derived from satellite imagery.Environmental Research Letters 3. stacks.iop.org/ERL/3/045011</datacred>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <title>Democratic Republic of the Congo woody above-ground biomass (tonnes/hectare)</title>
        <pubdate />
        <othercit />
        <origin>Woods Hole Research Center</origin>
        <onlink>http://app.databasin.org/app/pages/datasetPage.jsp?id=de26082bd4df4bbeabbaf14ae5195ece</onlink>
        <pubinfo>
          <publish />
          <pubplace />
        </pubinfo>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Alessandro Baccini</cntper>
          <cntorg>The Woods Hole Research Center</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <status>
      <progress />
      <update />
    </status>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>2000</sngdate>
        <current />
      </timeinfo>
    </timeperd>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekey>biomass</themekey>
        <themekey>carbon</themekey>
        <themekey>MODIS</themekey>
        <themekey>lidar</themekey>
        <themekey>GLAS</themekey>
        <themekey>regression tree</themekey>
        <themekey>Random Forest</themekey>
        <themekey>REDD</themekey>
        <themekey>DRC</themekey>
        <themekt>Data Basin tags</themekt>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <northbc>6.159818851887899</northbc>
        <eastbc>39.140901721107774</eastbc>
        <southbc>-13.827855769268684</southbc>
        <westbc>5.35371331061998</westbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr />
    </attracc>
    <complete />
    <lineage>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Consolidated Data Basin Info: Note&amp;#160;: this dataset was reprojected by CBI (datum was converted from a user-defined spherical to WGS 84, sinusoidal projection retained) for import into Data Basin. The original datasets can be downloaded at&amp;#160;http://www.whrc.org/mapping/pantropical/carbonmap2000.htm (http://www.whrc.org/mapping/pantropical/carbonmap2000.html)</procdesc>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Rowid</attrlabl>
        <attalias>Rowid</attalias>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdomv />
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>VALUE</attrlabl>
        <attalias>VALUE</attalias>
        <attrdef>VALUE</attrdef>
        <attrdomv />
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>BINVALUES</attrlabl>
        <attalias>BINVALUES</attalias>
        <attrdef>BINVALUES</attrdef>
        <attrdomv />
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>COUNT</attrlabl>
        <attalias>COUNT</attalias>
        <attrdef>COUNT</attrdef>
        <attrdomv />
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Data Basin</cntorg>
          <cntper>Data Basin Administrator</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>physical address</addrtype>
          <address>136 SW Washington Ave, Suite 202</address>
          <city>Corvallis</city>
          <state>OR</state>
          <postal>97333</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>541-757-0687</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>databasin_admin@consbio.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Democratic Republic of the Congo woody above-ground biomass (tonnes/hectare)</resdesc>
    <distliab>No warranty is made by Data Basin for use of this dataset.  No warranty is made by Data Basin regarding the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of this dataset. In no event shall Data Basin have any liability whatsoever for payment of any consequential, incidental, indirect, special, or tort damages of any kind, including, but not limited to, any loss of profits arising out of the use or reliance on the geographic or attribute data contained within this dataset or arising out of the delivery, installation, operation, or support by Data Basin.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname />
          <formvern>ArcGIS  10</formvern>
          <formspec />
          <filedec>No compression applied</filedec>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>http://app.databasin.org/app/pages/datasetPage.jsp?id=de26082bd4df4bbeabbaf14ae5195ece</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
            <accinstr>Download from http://databasin.org</accinstr>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
      <ordering>Download from http://databasin.org</ordering>
    </stdorder>
    <techpreq>ESRI ArcGIS Desktop and supporting operating systems.</techpreq>
  </distinfo>
</metadata>

